Wieslaw Z. Wisniewski Papers, 1939-1994 (bulk 1976-1990)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Wieslaw Z. Wisniewski Papers, 1939-1994 (bulk 1976-1990)
MS 546
Wisniewski, Wieslaw Z.
The Wieslaw Z. Wisniewski Papers document the University of Arizona Lunar and Planetary Laboratory astronomer's research in the field of comets, stars, extra-galactic objects, and asteroids. This collection includes observational findings, research, and correspondence related to his research endeavors. The bulk of his research focused on near-Earth objects, especially asteroids.
9 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Lunar and Planetary Laboratory astronomer Dr. Wieslaw Z. Wisniewksi (1931-1994) was a notable expert on photometric standards, CCD photometry and photomultipliers. He focused on light curves of comets and minor planets, especially Earth-approaching objects. He was born on May 2, 1931 in Poland. In his correspondence he writes of how he lost his father to starvation and he himself nearly died from hunger while dealing with a Nazi occupied country. He was saved from starvation with the ending of the Second World War. Wisniewski also endured the communist regime in Poland. Despite the strife of a politically unstable country, he was successful. Wisniewski was a high school mathematics teacher from 1951-1953 while simultaneously working on an M.A. in Astronomy from Poznan University which he received in 1952. He secured a job as a research assistant at the Cracow Observatory of Jagiellonian University where he eventually moved up to the position of lecturer in 1954. He also participated as a Scientist of the International Geophysical Year Expedition from 1957-1959. Wisniewski resumed his position at Cracow Observatory as a senior lecturer in 1959. He received his D.Sc. in Astronomy from Jagiellonian University in 1962.
In 1963, Wisniewski took a leave of absence from Cracow Observatory to work as a research associate at the Lunar Planetary Laboratory at the University of Arizona. He worked extensively with Dr. Harold Johnson, who at the time was breaking new ground by using the UBV photometric system. Both scientists worked on a landmark study of over 5000 bright stars in UBV which they published in 1966. They also recorded observations of Seyfert Galaxies, RR Lyrae stars and supernovae. Wisniewski moved up in ranks as an assistant professor. During this time he was also to confirm that both comets Wolf and Harrington were in fact the same object resulting in the comet named P/Wolf-Harrington. He remained at the Lunar Planetary Laboratory until 1967.
After a brief four year homecoming to Cracow Observatory, he returned in 1971 to the Lunar Planetary Laboratory for the duration of his career. As his career progressed, Wisniewski's research did as well. He moved to using charge-coupled devices or CCD detectors which detect the UV, visible and near-infra light. He made hundreds of observations using this method. Wisniewski spent over three hundred nights per year observing on a variety of telescopes. He used the 28" and 61" telescopes on Mt. Bigelow, the 60" telescopes on Mt. Lemmon and Kitt Peak National Observatory, and even made the trek to Cerro Tololo in Chile. He collaborated extensively with many other astronomers including Theodore Faÿ, George Coyne, Dave Tholen, Tom Gehrels, and many other notable astronomers of his time. He worked on the light curve and taxonomic observations of hundreds of asteroids and multi-color photometry, participated in global observations such as International Halley Watch and 243 Ida and 951 Gaspra as part of the Galileo spacecraft's journey to Jupiter. He contributed early images of P/Shoemaker-Levy 9 to the astronomy community. Wisniewski has a minor planet named after him, (2256) Wisniewski. Wieslaw Z. Wisniewski died on Monday February 28, 1994.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 3 series.
Series I: Correspondence Files, 1966-1994
Series II: Research Files, 1939-1994
Subseries 1: Comets, 1970-1991
Subseries 2: Stars and Extra Galactic Objects, 1939-1993
Subseries 3: Asteroids, 1974-1994
Subseries 4: Proposals and Grants, 1977-1994
Subseries 5: Miscellaneous Research, 1975-1994
Series III: Scholarly Files, 1975-1993
Subseries 1: Publications, 1975-1993
Subseries 2: Book Reviews, 1986-1993
Subseries 3: Conferences and Meetings, 1988-1993
Scope and Content Note
Papers 1939-1994: This collection documents Wisniewski's astronomical research through the use of photometric standards, CCD photometry and photomultipliers. Wisniewski focused on light curves of comets and minor planets, especially Earth-approaching objects. The collection includes observations of comets, stars, extra-galactic objects, and asteroids as well as correspondence documenting the personal and professional relationships between Wisniewski and other scientists. The collection follows Wisniewski's original order. Materials include, but are not limited to letters, CCD photometry results, observation charts, black and white photos of CCD captures, and proposals at various research levels.
Coyne, George.; Faÿ, Theodore.; Gehrels, Tom.; Johnson, Harold.; Tholen, David.; Zellner, Benjamin.; American Astronomical Society.; Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory.; International Astronomical Union.; National Science Foundation.; Planetarium I Obserwatorium Astronomiczne.; University of Arizona. Lunar and Planetary Laboratory.; Asteroids.; Astronomy.; Comets -- Observations.; Galaxies.; Photometry.; Space.; Stars.; Telescopes.; Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory.; Kitt Peak National Observatory.; Mt. Lemmon Observatory.; Steward Observatory.; University of Arizona.
Container List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1966-1994
  Contains personal and professional correspondence maintained by Wisniewski and varies from professional colleagues and organizations to personal topics of interest.
  - A'Hearn, Michael F., 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Astronomical Society, 1977-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Astronomical Society Report, Draft Lunar Planetary Laboratory Report, 1981, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Banachiewicz, Tadeusz, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - B, 1982-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Candon, Pierre, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cerro Tololo International Observatory, 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Coyne, George, 1972-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - C, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Echevarría, Juan, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gehrels, Tom, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - International Astronomical Union, XVII General Assembly, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - H, 1978-1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - International Astronomical Union Commission 15, 1980-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Johnson, Harold, 1976-1980, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Kitt Peak National Observatory, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - K, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - L, 1974-1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Maslowski, Josef, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mufson, Stuart, 1978-1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - M, 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - National Research Council, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - National Science Foundation, 1966-1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Planetarium I Obserwatorium Astronomiczne, 1984-1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Planetary Science Institute (Polskie Towarzystwo Astronomiczne), 1981-1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Probst, Ronald G., 1981, 1982, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - P, 1982-1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Strittmatter, Peter, 1983-1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - S, 1974-1989 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - T, 1980-1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Wisniewski, Wieslaw Z., 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - W, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Zellner, Benjamin, 1977-1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Series 2: Research Files, 1939-1994
  - Subseries 1: Comets, 1970-1991
    Contains cometary observations made using the UBVRI process through CCD photometry. Files contain data charts, correspondence related specifically to the object, and some photos of the objects themselves. Additionally, any associated research proposals and articles are filed with the comet.
    - P/Arend-Rigaux Comet Observations and Ephemerides, 1976, 1984, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - P/Ashbrook-Jackson, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - P/Brooks 2, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - P/Borrelly and P/Kohoutek, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Comet Chernicki, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Comet Encke, 1970, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - P/Giacobini-Zinner, 1985, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Comet Grigg-Skjellerup, 1970-1991 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Halley Filters, 1970, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - P/Halley Observations, 1985, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - International Halley Watch, 1981-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - P/Helin, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - P/Klemola Compared to P/Brooks 2, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - P/Kopff, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - P/Neujmin 1: Ephemerides 1, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - P/Neujmin 1: Ephemerides 2, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - P/Neujmin 1: Data, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Comet Kohoutek, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - P/Shoemaker-Holmes, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 121 P/Shoemaker-Holt, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 121 P/Shoemaker-Levy, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Future Comets Observation Data, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "The Light Curve of the Nucleus of the Comet d'Arrest", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Standard Stars for Cometary Photometry", 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ground-Based Support, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - The Rotation Periods of Hyperion and Comet Gunn, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Comets, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 2: Stars and Extra Galactic Objects, 1939-1993
    Contains observations of stars and extra galactic objects made using the UBVRI process through CCD photometry. Files contain data charts, correspondence related specifically to the object, and some photos of the objects themselves. Additionally, any associated research proposals and articles are filed with the comet.
    - Elliptical Galaxies Observations/Photographs, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - NGC 7469 23" 02+08, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Spectrum Variability of B2 0738+31 (OI 363)", 1972, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - BL LAC Color Changes, 1976-1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Various Quasar (QSO) Finding Charts and Observations, 1970, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Uranus Observations, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Various Finding Charts, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Various Spectra (Alf Lyr), 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Star Observations for Chile-Cerro Telolo, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Vega: Correspondence, Observations and Papers, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - M CEP 8316, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - RW CEP, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - XX PER, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - ST CEP, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - S PER, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - BU GEM, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - WY Gem 42474, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - M Supergiants, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - RS Per, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - BU Per, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - FZ Per, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - U LAC, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - CE Tau-1845, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - TV GEM 2190, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - GK Tau, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - G2 Stars, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Cepheid Star Findings and Charts, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Reduced Cepheid Observations, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - ER Aur 40008000161, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - CY Aur 4000800125, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - BM Per 4006300090, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - HW Pup 4006800223, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - EV Agl 4000500165, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - AS Vul 4008800072, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - "RR Arietis-RR-Lyrae variability star in Ecliping system", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - VV 280 Cyg 1085850280, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - KX Cyg 4003100257, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - BI Cas 4001800087, 1976-1980, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - V 396 Cyg 4003100396, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - CN Sct 4007500114, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - V 1828 Sgr 4007201828, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - V 1996 Sgr 4007201996, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - GQ Vul 4008800199, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - CN Cep 400200114, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - V 438 Cyg 4003100438, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - V 609 Cyg 4003100609, undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - AA Ser Observe Continuously, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - AV Sgr 4007200075, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - V 554 Oph 400590554, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - V 541 Oph 4005900541, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - KR Aur Spectra and Stars, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - KR Aur, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - V 425 Cas, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - V 751 Cyg Like VZ Cet, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - RZ Vul, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - CE Sct, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - AA Tau, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - MCW 300, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - U + Image Intensifier Experiment, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - CCD Comments, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - CCD Tests, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - LPL CCD Cosmetics, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - BL Lac Objects Energy Distribution, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - BL Lac Fluxes, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Colors Versus Magnitude for BL Lac and Seyferts, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - BL Lac Observing Schedule, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - BL Lac, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - BL Lac 3C120, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - O -- B Stars, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Star Data, 1939-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - PHL 658, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 001 040, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - III Zw 2, 1978-1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - 0026 + 129 S, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 0049 + 171, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 0052 + 252, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 0106 + 13, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - NGC 404, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - 0109 22, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - 008 + 171 M, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - MK 358, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - MK 1015, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - 3C 66A, 1976-1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - MK 1037, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - 229 + 13, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - 3C68.2, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - A002 35 + 16, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - NGC 1052, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - MK 1055, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - 3C29.08, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - 0300 + 470, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - NGC 1275, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - HD 21110, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - 0323 + 02 Tapia, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 0414 + 009, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - 0420 - 01, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - 0422 + 00, 1977-1984 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - 0430 + 05 3C120, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - 0459 + 060, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - E Aur, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Ank 120, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - NGC 2110, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - 0710 + 118, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - MK 376, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - 0724 + 49, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - 0724 + 496, 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - 0735 + 17, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - 0736 + 01, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - 0738 + 031 = OI363, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - MK 79, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - 0742 + 31, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - 078 + 126, 1979-1989 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - 0750 + 54, 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - 0752 + 258, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - 0754 + 104, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - 0804 + 49, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - 0806 + 350, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - 0808 + 019, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - 818 - 12, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - 0823 - 223, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - 0827 + 024, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - 0829 + 046, 1979-1985 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - 0837 - 12, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - 847 + 19, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - OJ 287, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - 0906 + 48, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - 0953 + 25, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - 0952 + 179, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - 955 + 326, 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - C 332 (Wills) 0955 + 326, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - 09570561 double QSO, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - 1001 + 29 for Wills, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - 1004 013, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - 1011025, 1979-1985 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - 1012 + 008, undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - 1028 + 313, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - [MK] 421 Aperture Study, 1976-1985 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - 1121 + 423, undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - MK 180, 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - 1142 024, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - 1148 - 001, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - 115 + 169, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - 1156 + 295, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - 1202 + 281, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - NGC 4151, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - 1210 + 121, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - 1211 + 143, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - MK 437, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - 11215 + 030, 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - 1217 + 023, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - 1218 + 304, 1979-1985 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - ON 231 = W Com, 1978, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - 0912 + 297, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - 1223 + 252, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - 1225 + 317, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - 3C273, 1963-1986 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - 1229 - 021, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - 1229 + 204, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - NGC 4552, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - 104 - 306, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - MK 228, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - 1250 + 568 = 3C277.1, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - 1253 – 055 = 3C279, 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Anonymous Galaxy from S.T., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - MK 231, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - 1301 + 117, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - 1308 + 326, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - 1308 + 32, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Ton 155, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Ton 156, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - 1354 + 195, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - 1400 + 162, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - 1402 + 0416, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - 1416 + 067, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - 1418 + 54, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - 1425 + 267, undated (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - MK 748, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - 1456 - 084, 1977, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - 1510 - 084, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - 1512 + 370, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - 1525 + 227, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - 1538 + 149, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - 1545 + 21, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - 1546 + 02, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - 159385, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - 1612 + 261, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - 1618 + 177, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - 1635 + 119, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - 164 + 399, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - MK 501, 1976-1985 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - 1717 + 178, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - 1720 + 246, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - 1721 + 343, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - I Zw 1727 + 50, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - 1741 - 038, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Galactic Center, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - 3C371, undated (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - S9313 Lyr, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - 1828 + 480, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - UV-236, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - NGC 6814, undated (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - MK 509, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Star "A" Compared to MK 509 Spectrum for Reticon, undated (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - 2128-123, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - 2135-147, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - 159-125, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cyg V624, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - BL Lac 1981 Observations, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - BL Lacertae 200 + 042, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 2210 + 171, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 2201 + 310, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 2216 - 03, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - 2223 - 052 = 3C446, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 2251 + 178, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - 2251 + 113, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 2344 + 009, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - 3C454, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - 225407, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Blue Galaxy, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - B Star Project, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Stars and Extra Galactic Objects, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 3: Asteroids, 1974-1994
    Contains correspondence, asteroid charts, CCD photometry analysis of asteroids, articles and proposals related to the specific asteroids. Files are labeled according to Wisniewski’s original file label.
    - 4 Vesta, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - 30 Urania, 1987-1992 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - 109 Felicitas, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - 127 Johanna, 1985-1991 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - 132 Aethra, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - 149 Medusa, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - 199 Byblis, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - 243 Ida, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - 243 Ida I, II, III, September, 1990-November, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - 243 Ida, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - 298 Baptistina, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - 347 Pariana, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - 367 Amicitia, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - 391 Ingeborg, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - 428 Monachia, 1988-1993 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - 433 Eros Photometry, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 449 Hamburga, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - 453 Tea, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - 458 Hercynia, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - 486 Cremona, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - 532 Herculina, 1978, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - 540 Rosamunde, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - 587 Hypsipyle, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - 594 Mireille, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - 711 Marmulla, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - 722 Frieda, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - 727 Mette, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - 728 Leonisis, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - 770 Bali, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - 782 Montefiore, 1988-1992 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - 822 Lalage, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - 823 Sisigambis, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - 825 Tanina, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - 851 Zeissia, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - 853 Nansenia, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - 901 Brunsia, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - 905 Universitas, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - 944 Hidalgo, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - 951 Gaspra: Barucci, Antonella, 1982-1992 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - 951 Gaspra: South African Astronomical Observatory, 1985-1991 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - 951 Gaspra: CCD, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - 951 Gaspra: Comparisons to Nearby Objects, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - 951 Gaspra: Observing Report and Data, 1982-1992 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - 951 Gaspra: Observations, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 951 Gaspra, Observations, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 968 Petunia, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1009 Sirene, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1025 Riema, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1060 Magnolia, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 1078 Mentha, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1083 Salvia, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 1088 Witarka, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 1090 Sumida, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 1103 Sequoia, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 1117 Reginita, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - 1123 Shaplaya, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - 1131 Porzia, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - 1139 Atami, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)